The situation is getting tense with the threat of the bus line being shut down.
由於這條公交線路要取消，情況變得很緊張。
Protestors took their concerns to transit officials...
抗議者把要求送到公交部門，---
but talks broke down when the newly appointed alderman, Reginald Shannon...
但是談判中斷了，因為有個憤怒的抗議者 ---
was punched in the face by an angry protestor.
給新來的街區委員 Reginald Shannon 當臉一拳。
-Good evening, sir. -What's up, Nikki?
-晚上好，先生。 - 你好，Nikki?
I noticed you weren't at the party, so I thought...
是這樣，我發現你沒在派對上， 我想 ----
if there is anything you would like for me to do, I would be happy to.
如果你有用得著我的地方的話，我都會樂意去做。
Could I ask you something?
我可以問你一些事嗎？
Yes.
可以。
You seem like a nice girl.
知道嗎，你像是個好姑娘。
How did you get into this line of work?
你怎麼會選上這門工作？
where I majored in Theater and Communications.
我選擇了戲劇交流專業。
I did some extra work, and a few things that went straight to video.
我做了大量的工作， 有些工作還直接拍成了錄像帶。
Okay.
好的。
Can I ask you a question?
我能問你一個問題嗎？
Yeah, sure.
問吧，當然可以。
Since I've been here, you haven't really given me any assignments.
自從我來到這裡，你沒給我分配過工作。
I was wondering if you find me attractive.
我心裡十分納悶，難道我就這麼沒魅力？
I think you're....
我想，你 ---
I think you're very attractive. It's just that...
我想，你非常有魅力，只是因為 ---
I like to get to know people before I get involved.
我喜歡先把人好好認識了，再去進一步加深。
I don't mean to be out of line, sir...
我不願如此的不被人重視，先生 ---
but are you?
你呢？
Am I what?
我，什麼？
Trying to get to know somebody.
應當去認識認識人啊。
-lt is late, I'm out of here. -You need to take a cab.
- 太晚了，我回家了。 -  姑娘，你該叫輛出租車。
I'll be fine. I'm just gonna walk.
沒事的，我走回去。
Take a cab!
叫出租車！
I'll be fine. I'll walk.
沒事的，我步行。
Need a ride?
要搭車嗎？
Where are we going?
我們這是去哪兒？
I just thought I'd give you a little tour.
我想，我該帶你兜兜風了。
If you look over there, it's the Lincoln Memorial.
你看那邊， 那是林肯紀念堂。
Lincoln freed the slaves...
林肯解放了奴隸 ----
but before he did it, he said, "First you niggers got to build me a statue."
但在解放之前，他說， 「但你們黑人應先給我豎像。」
Right there is the Jefferson Memorial.
右邊那個，是傑佛森紀念堂。
Jefferson had a black mistress.
傑佛森有過一個黑人情婦。
He said, "All men are created equal, but black women got the nicest ass!"
他說過，「所有人來到這世界上都應平等， 但黑女人的屁股卻生得最漂亮。」
That's the Treasury.
這是財政部。
If you look real hard in the window, you can see Oprah counting her money.
如果你使勁地往裡瞧， 你可以看見 Oprah 在數她的錢。
$20 trillion one, $20 trillion two....
20 萬億零 1 ，20 萬億零 2 ，----
Hi, Oprah!
嗨哎，Oprah!
What's it like...
我很想知道，
traveling all over the country and meeting all those people?
旅行全國，跟各地的人交談，是個什麼滋味？
I like it. I like traveling, I like meeting the people.
這事我喜歡。我喜歡旅行。 我喜歡與人交談。
But sometimes, you don't know if people like you for you.
但有時，你並不知道，愛你的人是否是為了愛你。
-Know what I mean? -I like you for you.
- 懂我的意思嗎？ - 我對你是為愛而愛的。
And I think you're okay.
我想你夠意思。
-Just okay? -I'm just playing.
- 僅僅是夠意思？ - 說句笑話。
I forgot how nice D.C. was.
我已經忘了首都是多麼的漂亮。
I'm always working. I never get a chance to check it out.
我一直在工作， 一點出來看看的機會也沒有。
Maybe you need to take advantage of what's in front of you.
你眼前就放著大好機會，好好利用一下吧。
You never know, you may look up someday, and it might not be there.
誰知哪天你再抬頭看時，她已經不在那兒了。
Freeze!
不許動！
Put your hands up in the air and step away from Mr. Gilliam!
舉起雙手，退後，離開 Gilliam 先生！
It's okay!
這裡沒事。
-What the hell are you doing?
-  你們要幹什麼？ -  你在幹什麼？
You can't go dashing off in the middle of the night with some girl.
你不能深更半夜溜出來與某某姑娘約會。
Something's happened. We got to pack and get out of here!
有事件發生了。 收拾東西，我們要趕去那兒。
Somebody make sure she gets home safely.
請誰一定把她安全送回家。
We have a plane waiting for us.
飛機等著我們呢。
In Florida today, guns and explosives were found at a junior high school.
佛羅里達州的一所初中，發現槍支炸藥。
No one was injured in the incident, but with just six weeks till Election Day...
處理過程中，沒人受傷。 現在離選舉日只剩六個星期，---
this could be a hot-button issue for both parties.
這是個重大問題，兩黨都會高度重視的。
Now, back to the Jay-Z song already in progress.
現在請您繼續欣賞 Jay-Z 歌曲。
Muhammad, get me a gun in case another kid tries to get crazy.
Muhammad ，給我一支槍，預防萬一， 誰知哪個小子不會一下子衝動起來。
This could work in our favor. Florida is a big Second Amendment state.
這事件對我們是有用的。 佛羅里達是第二修正案的大州。
This is serious. This is not the Player's Ball.
要非常嚴肅，不是在玩球俱樂部。
You can cut into Lewis' numbers. Talk about the kids, not about the guns.
降低 Lewis 的支持率就看此舉。 談話重點放在孩子身上，不要說槍。
If I get shot, everybody is fired.
如果我挨槍，你們一個也別想逃過。
One question here.
這裡有人提問題。
There's been an outcry that something needs to be done about school violence.
街區委員 Gilliam， 早就有人呼籲採取具體步驟制止學校暴力。
What do you plan to do about this?
對此你的具體計劃是什麼？
I feel we need to talk to our kids....
我覺得我想同我們的孩子對話 ---
Excuse me.
恕我失陪。
Hello, children.
哈羅，孩子們。
Good morning.
早上好。
Pay attention. This is going to be a class: Bullshit 101.
大家看好。這裡要給大家開新課了： 如何說屁話 101。
Ladies and gentlemen, our American children are hurting today...
女士們，先生們： 我們美國孩子今天受到損害，
and we need to reach out to them...
我們應該伸出我們的雙臂---
and give them all a good old-fashioned American hug.
給他們一個傳統的美國式的擁抱。
America is the greatest country on the face of the earth...
美國是這個地球上的最偉大的國家， ---
and I want to say:
我要說的是：
God bless America!
天祐美國 ！
And no place else.
只佑美國。
Thank you. Thank you, children.
謝謝你們， 謝謝你們，孩子們。
No more bombs now. And don't use guns.
不要再玩炸彈了，不要再玩槍了。
-That went well. -Very touching.
- 進行得很好。 - 非常感人。
-The kids liked me. -You were very genuine.
- 孩子們喜歡我。 - 你本來就是名不虛傳嘛。
They responded.
他們有反應。
I tried to hug a girl and a boy so I wouldn't seem sexist.
我女孩子和男孩子都試著去抱， 性方面就找不到喳。
Welcome to the show, Alderman Gilliam.
歡迎你來到這個舞台，街區委員 Gilliam 。
Surprised you're not somewhere with your girlfriend.
喲，天大的驚奇，你怎麼不去陪你可愛的女朋友了？
How do you know about her?
你怎麼會知道她？
I'm the government. I know everything.
我是政府，孩子，我知道一切。
We really should debate.
先生，我們很需要來場辯論。
Let's get something straight.
讓我打開天窗說亮話，Gilliam 。
I don't know you, and I don't like you.
我不認識你，我不喜歡你。
Party's over. I'm fixing to whip your ass.
好戲收場了，Gilliam 。我會狠狠抽你的屁股。
You got it?
懂了嗎？
Sir, we really should debate.
先生，我們很需要來場辯論。
God bless America, and no place else.
天祐美國 ！只佑美國。
Sir, we just got this off the uplink.
先生，我們從衛星上剛搞到這份報告。
What is it?
什麼內容？
An off-the-record comment by Mays Gilliam.
Mays Gilliam 的一份非正式評論。
-Bad? -Yes, sir.
- 是份壞東西？ - 是的，先生。
Good work.
非常出色。
It's on! Guys, come here!
噢，電視來了，快到這邊來。
...Lewis was on the scene comforting parents and students.
...Lewis 在現場安慰家長和學生。
The press is in Lewis' back pocket.
輿論工具是Lewis 的囊中之物。
In this CNB News exclusive, our cameras caught Gilliam...
這是 CNB 特別新聞報道。 我們的鏡頭抓住了Gilliam...
making what was arguably the most controversial statement of the day.
他說出了一句可能引起巨大爭議的話：
They act like us. We're bombing countries all the time.
「他們同我們一樣， 我們每時不刻地在轟炸別人的國家。」
If I was 12, I'd have a gun, too.
「如果我是 12 歲，也早就佩槍了。」
Tell me you didn't say that.
告訴我你不曾說過這些話。
I didn't know the camera was on me. I was playing around with some sound guy.
我不知道鏡頭對準著我。 我正在和一些唱歌的孩子在玩。
You didn't know the camera was on you?
你不知道照相機對準著你？
Of course it's on you. It's always on you! You're running for President!
當然對準你，它始終對準著你。 你是在競選總統！你該死！
I told you....
從第一天起，我就告訴過你，---
This is all your fault!
你沒嘴說我，這全是你的過錯。
Gilliam is under investigation by the FBI...
Gilliam 現在已經受到FBI 的調查。
for his involvement with this man...
因為他同這個人有牽連 ---
friend and associate and accused drug lord, Warren Pryor.
大毒犯： Warren Pryor，也是他的朋友和合夥人。
-Lord, we're going to jail. -We're not going to jail.
- 天啊，我們要進監獄了。 - 不會進的。
Is it true?
是真的嗎？
What's up, Warren?
哎，你好， Warren 。
I know him, but I don't drug-lord know him.
我認識他，但我不知道他是個毒梟。
It's just a guy I say "What's up?" to. But I don't know him know him.
他只是我的一個僅僅打打招呼的街坊。 其他哪有什麼關係。
Do you have drugs on you? Get them off, I'm not going to jail for you.
你身上藏有毒品沒有。 把他們扔掉，我可不跟你進監獄。
Are you on the pipe?
你吸不吸毒？
This is messed up This really sucks
真是一團糟。 真正叫人莫名其妙。
Every time you're doing good trouble just pops up
任何時候，只要你做出了一點成績，麻煩就接踵而來。
He doesn't know what he's gonna do
他不知道怎麼去對付這個局面。
This is messed up This really sucks
真是一團糟。 真正叫人莫名其妙。
Keep your head up, it's your best bet
抬起你的頭來，拚搏就在今朝。
Let's hope the election's not through
讓我們希望選舉沒有拋棄他，
If you see Mays Gilliam, please do not call the authorities.
如果你看見 Mays Gilliam ， 請不要報告當局，
Just do whatever you can to make his life a living hell.
除此之外，你高興怎樣待他就怎樣待他， 讓他像生活在地獄裡一樣。
No more questions!
不再回答任何問題。
If I see Mays Gilliam, I'll bust a cap in his ass.
如果我看見 Mays Gilliam ， 我就踹他一腳。
Gilliam is done and Big Dave says, "Waa-waa!"
Gilliam 完蛋了。 Big Dave 說一聲：「玩完」。
Oh, God.
哦，我的老天。
What am I going to do?
我下面怎麼辦？
What are you worried about? Your face isn't on the side of a bus.
你有什麼好急的，汽車兩邊印得又不是你的尊容。
I'll be the one taking a hit for this.
遭殃的只是我。
Get me on the news so I can apologize. That's what the people want to hear.
安排我上新聞，我去做檢討。 人們要聽我的道歉。
You're probably right.
說起來這主意不錯。
Make a statement of some kind, try and sound sincere--
發表一個聲明還是其他形式， 說得誠懇一些 ---
Just give me a break!
給我省點精神吧。
You think you can say you're sorry and all of this will go away?
你以為說聲對不起，事情就大事化小，小事化了了？
Mays, you're running for President of the United States of America.
Mays，你在競選美利堅合眾國的總統。
Do you have any idea why they chose you?
你有沒有仔細想過，他們為什麼選你出來嗎？
-We picked you because-- -Shut up!
- 我們把你選出來，是因為 --- - 住你的嘴！
You're here to lose.
選你出來就是來輸的，Mays 。
Arnot picked you so you could lose.
Arnot 指定你去，因為你容易輸。
Think about it.
自己想想吧。
If they had any idea they could win this thing...
如果他們知道他們自己有一絲希望贏選，
do you think they would have chosen an ignorant-ass nigger like you?
你覺得他們會把這個機會讓給一個 你這樣的天真黑屁股蛋嗎？
Wait up.
等等。
You're not calling me an ignorant nigger...
我想，你不再會叫我天真的黑 ---
and thinking you're staying on my bus.
因為你意識到你是乘坐在我的汽車上。
I am not getting off this bus. We're in the middle of nowhere--
我不下汽車， 因為我們正在開往沒有目的地的途中。
Now you need a ride from an ignorant nigger.
這就是說你還需要乘坐天真黑鬼的車子。
I am not getting off this bus!
我絕不下車。
Apologize.
- 那就道歉。 - 想得美。
Security!
保安！
Damn you, Mays Gilliam!
該死的你， Mays Gilliam ！
You knew about this all along?
你也是自始至終知道內情的？
Is there trouble inside the Gilliam campaign?
「Gilliam 的競選班子出問題了嗎？」
That's what Washington insiders want to know after Gilliam's chief advisor...
在Gilliam 的顧問主任 Debra Lassiter 離開競選活動之後，
Debra Lassiter, left the campaign trail.
這是華盛頓當局想要知道的情況。
Down in the polls, Gilliam still has no running mate.
支持率在下降， 而 Gilliam 還是沒有競選搭檔。
Sources say the Teamsters may endorse Lewis.
有消息說，駕駛人工會將表態支持 Lewis 。
Did Gilliam kill JonBenet Ramsay? Police want to know.
是 Gilliam 殺了 JonBenet Ramsay 嗎？ 警方想要知道回答。
The big question: Where is Mays Gilliam?
最大的問題就是， Mays Gilliam 在哪裡？
I'll tell you where he's at. He's with his peeps!
我告訴你他在哪裡。 他躲在洞裡。
-Hello? -You up?
- 喂。 -  你好。
I was hoping you'd call. Are you okay?
我在等你電話呢。你人在哪裡？你好嗎？
I don't know. I guess I'm all right.
我不知道。估計還可以。
Come on, talk to Mama.
可以就好，有委屈就吐吧。
I don't know. It seems like they're trying to get me.
天知道。 好像他們要整死我。
Everywhere I turn, they're trying to put a foot in my ass.
不管我到哪裡，他們都會伸出腳來踹我屁股。
After what you said, you need a foot put up in your ass.
是你自己說的， 你需要有腳踹你的屁股。
What did you expect? They would just make you President?
你在等什麼？ 等他們讓你當總統？
They take a poll for everything I do.
我做的任何一件事，他們都進民意測驗。
You ever been to a horserace? My dad used to take me when I was little.
你去看過馬賽沒有？ 小時候我爸帶我去過。
The horses wear blinders.
那些馬都戴著眼罩。
They don't even see each other. They just run their race.
它們看不見其他的馬。 它們就是跑。
So don't worry about Lewis, don't worry about the press...
所以你不必考慮 Lewis, 不必計較新聞報導 ---
just run your race.
你跑你的路。
Let me ask you something.
好吧，那我有話要問問你
Okay.
問吧。
What are you wearing?
你身上穿得是什麼？
Now, you know you need to stop.
噢，現在是你掛電話的時候了。
Man, news travels fast.
好傢伙，新聞跑得太快了。
Not 10 minutes after you fired me, I had two offers for jobs.
你解雇我不到十分鐘， 已經有兩個地方叫我去上班了。
Good offers.
非常好啊。
What are you doing here?
你在這裡做什麼？
I know you got no reason to trust me, but I'm asking you to.
我知道你沒有理由再相信我， 但我還是這樣要求你。
You've got five weeks left.
時間還剩五個星期。
I know Lassiter is out, but I think...
我知道Lassiter 走了，但我想 ---
I can help you do this.
我有能力幫你搞下去。
I want to help you.
我要幫助你。
And I'm sorry, Mays.
我向你道歉， Mays 。
I don't know what else to say...
其他我不知道還能說什麼，---
but as bad as things look, I don't think you should quit.
儘管情況很糟， 但我想你不應該就此屈服。
Who said I was quitting?
誰說我屈服了？
I wish I could quit.
能屈服，倒也省心嘍。
I wish it was that easy.
但願一切順利。
You're lucky.
你很幸運。
You are so lucky. You don't know how good you got it.
你真是很幸運。 你不知道你這樣有多舒服。
You just represent yourself.
因為你只代表你自己。
Me?
我呢？
I represent my whole race.
我代表我的種族。
If I quit...
如果我屈服，---
there won't be another black candidate for 50 years.
以後 50 年裡也不會有黑人出來競選。
All right.
好吧。
We can get rid of the school thing with a statement that will blow things over.
我們可以在學校那件事上點一把火， 那火會很快燒起來的。
But we need a running mate.
但是，你需要一個競選搭檔。
Who am I supposed to pick? Nobody wants to run with me.
我該選誰呢？ 沒人願意同我一齊競選啊。
We need somebody we can trust.
我們要一個我們可以信賴的人。
Who do you trust?
誰是你信賴的人？
In the midst of his own Cinderella story...
在他自己這個灰姑娘般故事的迷霧之中，---
presidential candidate Gilliam is shaking it up.
總統候選人 Gilliam 終於鑽出來了。
He's chosen his brother, Mitch Gilliam...
他選定他的兄弟， Mitch Gilliam ---
a bail bondsman from Chicago, as his running mate.
芝加哥的一位假釋擔保人， 做他的競選搭檔。
Political analysts say this may be too little, too late.
政治評論員說，這種搭檔可能太小， 也太遲了。
Hi, I'm with the Pork Commission--
嗨哎，我支持肉食品局---
I'm from the Athlete's Foot--
嗨哎，我是「運動員之腳」來的，---.
Brother!
兄弟！
Can you get my demo tape to somebody--
你能把我的樣碟送交給誰嗎？
Are these your bags?
這些是你的行李嗎，先生？
Look at my shoes and at the bags. Shut up and follow me.
看看我的鞋子，再看包。 閉上你的嘴，跟著我。
Back up.
向後退。
What do you have to say about your brother's controversial comments?
Gilliam 先生，你對你兄弟的有爭議的談話想說些什麼？
My gosh, lady, my brother said he was sorry. Let it go.
哎呀，這位女士，我兄弟說過了，是他的不對。 請你免提。
See, that's why nobody like your ass.
要識趣，否則屁股沒人要。
We got work to do. We way behind in the polls.
我們要把工作做起來。 我們的支持率還掉在後面。
-Am I getting paid for this? -Yeah.
- 這份工作有工資嗎？ - 當然有啊。
You're running for the vice presidency. You're a bail bondsman.
你想競選美國副總統。 你是假釋擔保人。
You have no Washington experience, no political experience or connections.
你沒有國家管理經驗，你沒有從政經驗， 聯絡溝通也沒有。
How does being a bail bondsman qualify you to be Vice President?
那麼，一個假釋擔保人怎麼會有資格去 競選美利堅合眾國的副總統呢？
I am a bail bondsman.
我這個假釋擔保人是這麼做的：
People come to me when they in trouble, like the USA.
人們有了難處時就來找我， 我們國家也是這樣。
We bail people out. We bail out Mexico...
我們幫助人們走出困境。我們幫助墨西哥走出困境。
the savings and loan, the airline industry.
我們幫助了銀行，我們幫助了飛機行業。
Now you ask me, sir, what qualify me to run for Vice President.
現在你問，先生，你有什麼資格競選副總統呢？
When the country is in trouble, I'll bail them out.
在國家有難處的時候，我能幫她走出困境。
Hold that thought. We have a caller from Detroit.
你先等一下，底特律有扣應電話進來。
Mitch! Why you looking around? It's Reggie.... Where my money at?
哎，Mitch ！ Mitch ！ 別四周瞎看， 是我， Reggie... 我的錢在哪裡？
Don't call me with that bullshit! You see I'm on TV.
這點屁事也打電話？ 沒看見我在電視上。
What about NATO?
NATO怎麼樣？ 你對 NATO 有什麼看法？
I never met Nato. I don't talk about people behind their back.
我從來沒見過Nato 。絕對不知有這個人。 我不在人的背後說人。
NATO is the North Atlantic Treaty Organization.
NATO是北大西洋公約組織。
But you have to know these things.
但是這些事你非知不可啊。
Do you know Nato Jacobs?
你認識Nato Jacobs 嗎？
I'm sorry, I haven't met the gentleman.
對不起，我不認識這個人。
That's what I said.
這就是我說的。
You know nothing about Nato? I know nothing about NATO.
既然你能不認識 Nato， 幹嘛非得我懂 NATO.
Why are you out here since inmates don't have the right to vote?
你為什麼到這裡來，犯人並無選舉權呀？
It's not about the vote. We're looking out for the convicts.
我們不是為選票而來， 我們是來觀察悔罪表現。
We want to make sure when they get out that they stay out.
我們要知道，他們將來釋放了，肯定不想再回來。
The better the education, they become more productive citizens.
教育越到家，積極的公民就越多。 讓我兄弟說幾句。
Mitch! What's up?
Mitch ！你好啊，夥計。
Shorty G!
Shorty G!
It's good to see you, boy!
好久沒見了，你好啊。
This is Shorty G. I arrested his ass. I thought you got the chair, boy.
這是 Shorty G。我逮住了他的屁股。 凳子已經給你放好了。
Mr. Gilliam, how would you deal with white-collar crime?
Gilliam 先生，白領階層的犯罪你準備如何解決？
There's no such thing as white-collar crime.
首先我要說的是， 天下沒有白領階層犯罪這回事。
And there's no such thing as black-on-black crime.
當然，天下也沒有黑對黑犯罪這回事。
Crime is crime.
犯罪就是犯罪。
I don't care if you have a white collar or a tank top.
我的意思就是， 我不管你是穿白領的，還是穿汗背心的，
If you rob me, I'll whup your ass.
你來搶我的錢，我就要你的屁股好看。
I'm Janet Silvers reporting live in D.C., where transit operators....
我是Janet Silvers 自首都現場轉播 公交司機---
-I wish we'd get into the White House. -To have a cookout?
-  我現在要是進了白宮多好。 - 搞次野餐會？
They were just talking about your ward.
他們正在談論你的街區。
What's going on down there?
那裡出什麼事了？
They want to cut bus service until they finish construction. I should go.
他們要取消公交線路，搞商場建築。我該去那裡。
-So you can blow up the bus line? -One thing at a time.
-  你想你能回復線路？ -  一件一件來。
The Teamsters haven't endorsed Lewis yet. Our numbers are going up.
駕駛人工會還沒表態支持 Lewis 。 我們的數字上升了。
If we want a real shot at this thing, we got to get Lewis to debate.
如果我們要想數字升得快一些， 我們必須找 Lewis 辯論。
He knows that. That's why he won't.
他也知道，所以他老避著。
He's avoiding me like he owes me child support.
他躲著我，好像欠了孩子的撫養費似的。
He is scared. He's holding the ball, hoping the clock will run out.
他患得患失。把球抓在手上，就等終場的哨子。
That's a punk move. Ducking and hiding like a little bitch!
這是流氓行為。 托時間，鬼鬼祟祟，像個小婊子。
That may be, but he won't debate you because you call him a little bitch.
說的也是，但他不會來同你辯論， 因為你叫他小婊子。
What this community needs--
這個社區需要的是 ---
Is for you to debate me right now!
需要的是，請你同我現在就來辯論。
Tell the people that!
把這話告訴大家。
I thought I told you that we won't stop.
告訴過你，不來辯論，絕不罷休！
Now, my agenda--
現在我的議事日程是 ---
I'll tell you about our agenda.
我來匯報我們的議事日程。
It's to have a debate right now!
我們的議事日程就是：辯論會必須立即召開。
Get rid of this zero and talk to the hero.
這種空談家理他做什麼，你應該和英雄多談談。
You got time to jog, but not to debate?
你有時間練跑，卻沒有時間辯論？
You can run, but you can't hide.
你能跑，但你跑不掉。
I thought I told you we won't stop.
告訴過你，不來辯論，絕不罷休！
What you looking for, the news? The news is we want to debate!
你在看什麼，新聞？ 新聞就是我們要求辯論。
-Why did you change the channel? -He's scared!
不辯！
-A word from our sponsor. -We want to debate!
- 我們的支持者高喊： - 請出來辯論。
I thought I told you that we won't stop.
告訴過你，不來辯論，絕不罷休！
Yo, Lewis!
唷，Lewis！
Your mother's ass is so big, when she sits down she's three feet taller.
你媽媽的屁股大得出奇啊， 她一坐下來，反而高了三尺。
Yo, Lewis! Your mother's got a really big ass!
唷，Lewis！ 你媽媽有個大的出奇的屁股。
Sir, it's time we prepare for a debate.
先生，該研究一下辯論的事情了。
Give me one good reason I should debate that jerk.
給我一條好理由我非得去同這些白癡辯論。
-He talked about your mother! -So what?
- 他們把你母親掛在了嘴上。先生。 - 那怎麼樣？
Are you going to just let him talk about me like that?
你打算讓他們這樣在外面說我？
After some inventive chiding on the part of Alderman Mays Gilliam...
經過街區委員Mays Gilliam 陣營一陣騷擾性的邀請，
Vice President Lewis has finally agreed to one debate...
副總統 Lewis 最後同意進行一次辯論 ---
the night before the election.
時間放在選舉日前夕。 〔 離選舉日：一星期〕 〔Lewis : 59%     Giliam : 41%〕
So, baby brother, this is it. You ready?
哎，小弟，終於來了。你準備好了嗎？
All right, I guess.
八九不離十。
You guess? You don't know? You either ready or you ain't.
八九？沒把握說十？ 我要你十十不離十。
What's your problem? I'm ready, okay?
看你急的，急什麼？ 我我我已經準備好了，放心了吧？
No, you ain't. Look at you. If you call this ready, this won't get it.
不，心放不下。你看你。 這身打扮你說準備好了，要壞事的。
Dress for the job you want, not for the job you got.
找工作要穿找工作的打扮。 不能穿工作敲定後的打扮。
You ain't talking about my clothes.
我知道你說來說去就是說我的衣著。
Come on now. This ain't about me.
哎，你怎麼啦，這裡沒有我。
If I got a good idea, it shouldn't matter what the hell I'm wearing!
如果我的辯論讓人們接受，打扮不打扮的 有什麼關係。
You know you messed up, man.
這麼說，你邋遢你自己是知道的，兄弟。
I'm telling you right now.
現在我跟你這麼說，
You know, this ain't about me!
要知道，這裡沒有我。
Lewis ain't no punk. He ain't no joke.
Lewis 不是小流氓。不是來玩的。
That man has been Vice President for eight years.
這人已經當了八年副總統。
He's a war hero. He's Sharon Stone's cousin.
他是個戰鬥英雄。 他是 Sharon Stone 的表兄弟。
You better come correct.
你不一絲不苟的正確，怎麼行？
Yeah? Well, I got us this far!
是嗎？你沒看見我已經一路殺到這兒了嗎？
This is as far as you're going to get!
你要的東西還遠著呢。
-It's like that? -That's the way it is.
- 你打下三路？ - 該出手時就出手。
Geller and them up there pumping your head up.
你在他家門外，昂起頭亂叫，
But Lewis will smack it back down!
但是 Lewis 也是會狠狠回甩你耳光的。
Oh, my God.
噢，不好。
Little brother, you all right?
小弟，沒事吧？
That's what your ass get.
你這傻瓜的下場。
You need anything? Because it look like you need some help.
要什麼東西嗎？因為看上去你需要一點幫助。
You gonna get yours! I'll tell Ma!
你也有叫救命的時候的，我去告訴媽媽。
You better not tell!
千萬不要去告狀。
Hello?
喂？
Don't intrude in my life anymore. I don't want to have anything to do with you...
喂， Mays。請聽著， 請別再侵入我的生活。 我不會再為你出謀劃策任何一件事了，---
not after the way you treated me.
這也不是因為你上次這麼待我而起的。
I'm sorry I threw you off the bus. It was wrong.
我把你趕下汽車，我向你道歉。 我做錯了。
I couldn't take what you were saying.
你當時的話我實在受不了。
What do you want?
Mays ，你想要什麼？
I want to win.
我想要贏。
Welcome to New York City for the 2004 Presidential Debates.
歡迎你來到紐約市2004 年總統辯論會場。
Where is he?
他在哪裡？
He was right behind me. Should I look for him?
剛才還在我身後的。 我去找找看？
-They're getting nervous. -We've got to do something.
- 到這時候人都會緊張的。 - 我們都分頭準備一下。
-I can do something. -No!
- 我也去準備準備。 - 不用了。
Ladies and gentlemen, Vice President Brian Lewis.
女士們，先生們， 副總統 Brian Lewis.
Wait. Here they come.
別急，來了，他們來了。
Sweet.
甜美啊。
Hello, Martin.
你好， Martin 。
Sorry I'm late. I had to change.
對不起，遲到了。非得我換衣服。
-Mr. Earl, nice to see you. -Nice to see you too, sir.
Earl 先生，你好。
Let's move.
我們去吧。
There are 250 million people out there deciding who to vote for.
Mays ，2 億5 千萬雙眼睛在看著，決定把票投給誰。
They all know Lewis didn't want to debate you. Show them why.
所有的人都知道Lewis 不願和你辯論。
-Stay focused. -Take your time.
抓住重點。
If he get out of pocket, put your foot in his ass.
如果他出言不遜， 你過去踹他屁股。
By the way, nice suit.
我插一句，這套衣服漂亮。
-"Fuh-buh"? -Fubu.
法霸？
Even I knew that.
連我都知道。
Ladies and gentlemen, Alderman Mays Gilliam.
女士們，先生們， 街區委員 Mays Gilliam。
Yo, when's Martin coming on, man?
唷， Martin  什麼時候出場，老兄？
My momma told me to whup your ass.
老媽說了，要我恨揍你的屁股。
The first question is directed by coin flip to the Vice President.
根據拋分幣，第一個問題先問副總統。
Vice President Lewis...
副總統 Lewis ，
what steps should be taken to limit our youth's access...
為阻止我們的青少年接觸武器， 我們應當採取 ---
to violent materials?
哪些步驟？
Our American children's futures are at stake here.
這個問題對我們美國孩子是個嚴重問題。
We need to study this issue, and appropriate legislation...
我們需要認真研究，做出相適應的立法，---
that will return us to an America we can be proud of.
如此才能使我們重新成為一個自豪的美國人。
God bless America, and no place else.
天祐美國，只佑美國。
Alderman Gilliam, same question, please.
街區委員 Gilliam ，同一問題，請回答。
How do we limit violent material? Turn it off.
如何限制暴力工具？剷除它們。
And if the kids cut it back on, knock them out.
如果你的孩子把它偷偷帶回家， 把你的孩子趕出去。
That's why I don't smoke.
這就是我沒染上煙癮的道理。
When I was a kid, my daddy caught me smoking...
小時候我吸煙，被我爸抓住，
and he knocked me out!
他把我趕出去。
And to this day, I don't smoke. Not because I'm scared of cancer.
直到今天，我沒敢吸。 可我並不怕生癌。
I don't smoke because I think my dad is going to walk through that door...
我不吸煙，是因為我怕我爸從門裡走出來，
and knock me the hell out!
一把把我甩到街上去。
Knock out your kids. It helps.
把你的孩子趕出去。這辦法靈。
Vice President Lewis...
副總統 Lewis...
with over 10,000 gun deaths per year in the United States...
美國每年因槍擊死亡的人數已經逾萬，
do you believe we need stricter gun control laws?
你是否認為我們需要更為嚴格的槍支管理法？
I don't think we need more gun control.
我不認為我們不需要再立法，
I say we enforce the laws that are already on the books.
我說我們應當加強執行現有法律。 它們都已經寫好了。
The problem is, nobody reads the books.
問題是，沒人去讀這些法律。
We need to start putting laws on videos...
我們需要對電視制定法律，
because everybody watches videos, MTV, BET.
因為每個人都看電視：MTV,，BET 。
We need to put some laws on the Nelly video.
我們要對 Nelly 電視進行法制管理。
If you had laws on a Destiny's Child video right now, you could stop crime.
如果你現在就對Destiny 兒童電視作出管理， 說不定就制止了犯罪現象。
-We already have gun licensing. -But that's only to carry the gun.
- 我們已經發放槍支憑證了。 - 但那只是你可不可以帶槍。
Let the people decide.
那我們就讓民眾來決定。
The people can't decide. The people are too busy getting shot in the ass.
民眾沒法決定， 民眾屁股上挨槍子兒，逃還來不及呢。
That's my brother.
那是我的兄弟。
That's another reason he's not qualified.
我說他不夠格，這裡就是另外一個原因。
Because I had the good sense to pick my big brother to be my running mate?
為什麼？就因為我慧眼識英雄 ， 選中我的哥哥做我的競選搭檔？
I didn't come here to argue with you.
你對，你對，我不是來同你吵架的。
Yes, you did. We're having a debate. A debate ain't nothing but an argument.
不對，你是來吵架的。我們來此進行辯論。 辯論就是吵架。
A debate isn't an argument.
辯論不是吵架。
-Yes, it is. -No, it isn't.
- 是的，就是吵架。 -  不是，不是吵架。
I know you are, but what am l?
我瞭解你，你瞭解我嗎？
Can we just move on? This is ridiculous.
把辯論進行下去，這樣對嘴愚蠢透了。
Our next question comes from--
先生們，下一個問題來自，---
I have a question.
我有一個問題，
Would you like our reception to be buffet style or formal seating?
招待會你喜歡散席形式，還是正規的坐席形式？
If you put Robert next to Nelson...
如果你把 Robert 排在 Nelson旁邊，
he'll be very angry because he wanted to be your best man.
他會很生氣，因為他想同你坐在一齊。
Security.
保安。
I love you so much--
我無限愛你，---
The candidates have agreed upon a short closing speech.
雙方都同意發表一則簡短的結束語。
Vice President Lewis won the coin toss.
副總統 Lewis ，拋分幣，又輪到你先說。
He has elected to go first.
現在請他發言。
Thank you.
謝謝大家。
-No, it isn't. -Yes, it is!
-  不是，不是吵架。 - 是的，就是吵架。
Tonight you have seen two different men...
今晚，你們看見兩個非常不相同的人，
with two very different points of view, battle to win your vote.
帶著非常不相同的觀點， 在此爭取你們的選票。
And this is what America is all about.
這就是美國精神。
As we've seen tonight...
今晚我們都已看到，
Alderman Gilliam can be captivating and entertaining.
街區委員 Gilliam 有吸引力，能讓大家輕鬆愉快。
But America needs more than that from its Commander in Chief.
但是美國人要求它們的領袖具有更多的本事。
To lead America, it takes experience.
要領導美國，你需要經驗。
Now, I've been Vice President for the last eight years.
過去八年來，我的工作是做副總統，
I'm a war hero, and I'm Sharon Stone's cousin.
我是戰鬥英雄。 我是Sharon Stone 的表弟。
And to me, America is like a fine performance car.
對我來說， 美國就像我玩熟的一輛好車。
And now is not the time...
現在還不是時候，
to turn this fine vehicle we call America...
把這輛這麼好的車--我們叫它美國--
over to the hands of an amateur.
交到一個生手手中。
I'm Brian Lewis, and I am your last chance.
我是Brian Lewis ，我才是你們最好的選擇。
God bless America, and no place else.
天祐美國，只佑美國。
Yeah, it's over now.
啊耶，你終於完了。
Why do you have to be so negative?
為什麼你對他如此反感？
Give me five.
擊掌相慶！
Thank you.
謝謝大家。
Hold it!
請大家息掌。
You're right, Vice President Lewis. I am an amateur.
你說得很對，副總統 Lewis ， 我是個生手。
When it comes to creating so many enemies...
我們到處樹敵，現在，
that we need billions of dollars to protect ourselves, I'm an amateur.
需要億萬億萬的錢來保護我們自己，
When it comes to paying farmers not to grow food...
付錢給農民，叫他們不要種糧食，
while people in this country starve every day, I'm an amateur.
而這個國家裡每天還有許多人在挨餓，
When it comes to creating a drug policy that makes crack and heroin...
藥品價格訂得如此之高，
But there's nothing wrong with being an amateur.
但是，是一個生手又有什麼錯？
The people that started the Underground Railroad were amateurs.
地鐵就是生手從無到有造出來的。
Martin Luther King was an amateur.
Martin Luther King 是生手起家的。
Have you ever been to Amateur Night at the Apollo?
你去過  Apollo 的「生手之晚」俱樂部嗎？
Some of the world's best talent was there:
世界上一些最偉大的天才都在那裡呆過：
James Brown, Luther Vandross, Rockwell, the Crown Heights Affair.
James Brown, Luther Vandross, Rockwell, the Crown Heights Affair.
-Hall and Oates! -The Fat Boys, Rob Base.
- Hall and Oates! - The Fat Boys, Rob Base.
But you wouldn't know nothing about that. Why?
但是你對此卻一點都不知道。這是為什麼呢？
Because when it comes to judging talent and potential...
這是因為，當你面對天才和有潛力的人才， 需要拿出判斷的時候，
you, my friend, are an amateur!
你，我的朋友，是一個生手！
-I believe the Alderman is over his time. -You had eight years to talk.
街區委員的時間我想已經用過頭了。
Now it's my turn. I'm getting mine!
現在輪到我說了，我有我的時間。 我有我的時間。
Ladies and gentlemen, hold your applause, please.
女士們，先生們， 請停止鼓掌。
How can you help the poor if you never been poor?
你從來沒窮過，你知道怎麼救窮？
How can you stop crime if you don't know no criminals?
你怎麼制止犯罪，如果你對罪犯絲毫不瞭解？
How can you make drug policy if you never smoked a chronic?
你從來不吸毒，你怎麼去制定抗毒政策？
How can you do that? Just a nickel bag!
你怎麼去堵，一包一包地搜？
I'm a real American.
我是一個真美國人。
I've been high, I've been robbed, I've been broke.
有過毒癮，被搶過，現在破產中。
My credit is horrible! They won't even take my cash!
我的信用差得，連用現金都沒人敢收。
You're always talking about, "God bless America, and no place else."
你張口閉口 「天祐美國，只佑美國。」
But isn't it obvious that God has blessed America?
但是，上帝只佑美國，這話是不是蠢了點。
America is the richest, most powerful nation on earth.
美國是世界上最富最強大的國家，
If America was a woman, it would be a big-titty woman.
如果美國是個女人， 她就是一個波霸女人。
And everybody loves a big-titty woman!
每個人都喜歡波霸。
So, in closing...
所以，歸根結底，
I'd like to say you are full of shit.
我要說的就是，你滿嘴噴糞。
"God bless America, and no place else."
「天祐美國，只佑美國」？
How about "God bless Haiti" or "God bless Africa"?
可以不可以天祐海地，天祐非洲？
How about "God bless Jamaica"?
可以不可以天祐牙買加？
I'm not talking about Jamaica, the beach tribes you all love.
我說的牙買加可不是你喜歡的那個酋長海灘，
I'm talking about stabbing Jamaica. That's what I'm talking about.
我說的是掙扎中的牙買加， 這是我要說的地方。
So, tonight I want to say: "God bless America, and everybody else!"
所以今天晚上我要說， 「天祐美國，天祐天下」
The whole world! God bless you!
天祐天下，天祐大家。
I'm Mays Gilliam, and I'm running for President of the United States of America.
我是 Mays Gilliam ，我在競選美利堅合眾國總統。
Ya heard?
聽見了嗎？
Now we can watch Martin!
現在我可以看 Martin 了吧。
-Hello? -Good morning, Mr. President.
喂？
-What time is it? -I think it's a little after 7::00.
- 什麼時候了？ - 大概過了七點了吧。
-Lisa, I need some help in here! -Will you wait a damn minute?
- Lisa ， 我這裡需要幫忙。 -  等上個一分鐘可以嗎？
I was so proud of you. You were so good last night.
Mays，我為你自豪， 昨晚你的表現太出色了。
I don't know. I might have to work.
不知道行不行，我大概在上班。
But if I don't see you tonight, I will see you soon.
今晚見不著你， 我也會很快見到你。
Just run your race, get out there, and do what you got to do, okay?
加緊競選，放下電話， 快去做你的正經事，好吧？
-I'll talk to you later. Bye. -All right.
- 我再給你打電話，再見。 - 好吧。
It's Election Day, Tuesday, November 8, 2004.
今天是選舉日。 2004 年，十一月八日，星期二。
The stage is set for what will be...
這次的選舉場面
one of the most dramatic campaign finales of all time.
將是歷屆選舉中最具戲劇性的一次。
The question everyone's asking is: "Who will America vote for?"
大家只問一個問題： 「美國人民將投誰的票？」
I voted for Mays Gilliam.
我投 Lewis 。
-I voted for big business. -I voted for Lewis.
- 我投做大事業的。 - 我選 Lewis 。
Who the fuck you think I'm voting for?
我操，你以為我會選誰？
There seems to be an agreement...
一項同意書似乎已經由---
between Washington, D.C., officials and transit authority operators...
市府、交通局和公交司機簽署，
regarding the shutdown of the 9th Ward bus line.
取消第九區的公交線路。
I don't see how they could do this to us.
我就不明白他們怎麼可以這樣對待我們。
People got to make money and get to work.
我們要去掙錢，要去上班。
-Show them how you do it. -The roof, the roof, the roof is on fire
- 怎麼做的，做給我看看。 - 屋頂，屋頂，屋頂已經著火了。
You're not gonna believe this. We got the Teamsters!
實在叫人不相信， 駕駛人工會投了我們的票。
-That's great, little brother! -They'll announce it at a press conference.
- 好極了，小弟。 - 他們將在記者會上宣佈。
You just have to go, shake hands, take photographs...
你要走出去，握手啊，和人合影啊，---
but it is yours.
不過這都是你的。
What's the matter?
嗨，出什麼事了？
If they shut down this bus service, I will drive you to work myself.
如果他們取消這條線路， 我來開車送你上班。
-I can't do it. -But it's Election Day!
- 我不去。 - 這是選舉日啊。
You have to get the endorsement. You said you want to win.
你要去爭取選票，你說過你要贏。
You can't snub the Teamsters. You want them to endorse Lewis?
你不能怠慢駕駛人工會。 你要他們去投 Lewis?
I'm not worried about Lewis. I'm running my race.
我不擔心 Lewis。 我競我的選。
Go ahead, baby brother. I got this.
你去吧，兄弟，這裡交給我了。
-You're just gonna let him go? -He's a grown man.
- 你就讓他這樣走了？ - 他是大人了。
They shut down the whole bus line. What can he do about that?
整條線路都取消了。你去也是無能為力的。
In the latest exit poll, Vice President Lewis has 51 percent of the vote.
這是最後一次民調， 副總統Lewis 支持率為 51%  ，---
Bring him back. He got to vote.
送他回去，他要投票。
...while Mays Gilliam is posting an impressive 47 percent.
--- 而 Mays Gilliam 的支持率也升到 47% 。
You gotta get to the back of the bus.
嘿嘿嘿，你應當到車的後面去上車。
I'm just playing. Come on.
開個玩笑，上來吧。
Now, he and Vice President Lewis are in a statistical dead heat.
現在，他和副總統 Lewis 在統計上都已到了終點。
Come on, hoes!
快，快，救火！
While Lewis and Mitch Gilliam have been working the campaign trail...
正當副總統 Lewis  和 Mitch Gilliam 忙著爭取選票的時候，
Mays Gilliam has been out driving people to work.
Mays Gilliam 卻去開車送民眾上班去了。
Damn it! Why didn't somebody around here think of this?
該死，為什麼這裡沒人想到去做這事？
Why am I not out there driving a damn bus?
為什麼我不出去駕駛公共汽車？
Get me an SUV, a minivan, a bus, a scooter...
給我SUV、微型房車、公共汽車、踏板車---
a motorcycle, or a rickshaw.
摩托車，沒有，人力車也行。
Get me some wheels, bitch!
只要是車就給我送來，混蛋！
Are you going uptown?
去市北嗎？
Come on. Wait a minute!
等等，等一下。
We could write our own vows!
我們可以去立誓。
I love you, Mays!
我愛你， Mays!
With the polls about 30 minutes from closing on the East Coast...
東岸離選舉結束還有半小時，
Mays Gilliam is actually ahead by several points.
Mays Gilliam 已經超前幾個百分點。
There is no question that Lewis has Texas.
毫無疑問，Lewis 可以拿下得克薩斯。
It seems clear Gilliam is going to take New York.
顯然，Gilliam 將贏下紐約州。
New York!
紐約！紐約！
It's likely Lewis will take Michigan.
Lewis  看上去將贏下密西根州
It looks like Gilliam might just pull an upset in lllinois.
看情況， Gilliam 可能在伊利諾斯州勝出。
Illinois!
伊利諾斯州！
Go, Mays!
衝啊，Mays!
This looks like it may come down to California.
照趨勢看，這股風將括向加州。
I need to know. How real is this? Can we win without California?
給我說說，這些報道究竟有多少是真的。 輸了加州，我會不會贏。
We stand a chance if you call your connections to the energy companies--
如果你能給能源公司打個電話， 我們還是有機會的。
No, you can't win without California.
輸了加州，你就沒法贏了。
What are you doing here?
你到這裡來幹什麼？
Shut up. You want to win, you'll do what I tell you.
閉嘴，如果你要贏，就照我的話去做。
Gilliam has over 90 percent minority turnout.
90% 以上的少數民族都去投票給 Gilliam了。
Whites are the majority, but they're not voting. They don't like you.
白人是多數民族，但他們不去投票，他們不喜歡你。
-I like you, sir. -Shut up.
-  我喜歡你，先生。 -  住嘴。
How can we turn this around?
我們怎樣做可以把它翻過來？
There's about one and a half hours left at the West Coast polls.
現在離西岸結票還有一個半小時，
If there's a leak saying Gilliam is going to win, you'll get a late rush.
如果把 「Gilliam  將當選」的風聲放出去， 對你的選票會有一個良性刺激。
You get California, you get the election.
拿下加州，你就贏了。
It will make the 6:30 news if we do it now. We just have to put it out there.
現在就寫，可在6：30的新聞裡播出去。
-Can we do this? -We're the government. We can do anything.
- 我們能這麼做嗎？ - 我們是政府，我們什麼都能做。
The race for President now turns to the West Coast.
總統競選現在移到了西岸。
People, Armageddon is upon us and Big Dave is scared.
國民們，世界末日要降臨到我們頭上了。 Big Dave 心裡很害怕。
If these voting trends sustain, it's likely that for the first time in history...
如果競選勢頭保持原樣， 顯然，歷史上的第一次將會出現：
a black man will become President of the United States of America.
黑人當上美利堅合眾國的總統。
"I have a dream that one day...
「我有一個夢，有一天---」
"this nation will rise up...
「國民能夠挺起身來，」
"and live out the true meaning of its creed:
「過上真正符合信念的生活：」
"'We hold these truths to be self-evident:
「  『所有的人生而平等』，」
"'that all men are created equal. "'
「就是用來自我證明這一真理的。」
Checkmate.
將軍！
I, Richard Nixon, do solemnly swear....
我， Richard Nixon ，依法宣誓 ---
I, Ronald Reagan, do solemnly swear....
我，  Ronald Reagan ，依法宣誓 ---
The race for President is over.
總統競選結束了。
The election is now over.
選舉結束了。
-The race for President.... -...is over.
- 總統競選 --- - ---結束了。
The race for President is over.
總統競選結束了。
For the first time in history, a black man, Mays Gilliam...
歷史上第一次，黑人， Mays Gilliam...
will be the next President of the United States of America.
將是小一屆美利堅合眾國的總統。
Come here, brother.
來吧，兄弟。
-I love you, man! -I love you, too.
- 我愛你，兄弟。 - 我也愛你。
I appreciate it. Thanks a lot.
謝謝，謝謝，多謝。
Thank you.
謝謝你們。
We won! Aren't you happy?
我們贏了，我們贏了。你高興嗎？
-Can I have a massage? -Yes!
- 可以給我來次按摩嗎？ - 可以。
I won!
我也贏了。
There is no way in the world I could have ever done this without you.
這世界上沒有你，我是沒有辦法做到這些的。
You're damn right.
說得賊對。
We won! We did it! Yes!
我們贏了，我們到手了。好啊。
Look at my little brother!
看看我的小弟弟。
-Boy, I'm proud of you! Mr. President! -Mr. Vice President.
- -小傢伙，我為你自豪，總統先生。 - 副總統先生。
You're the man! You ain't got to worry about no assassinations or nothing.
你是個好小子。
They sure don't want me to be the next President.
他們肯定不原意我當下一任總統的。
You can raise taxes, start a war....
你可以加稅，發動戰爭，---
Mays Gilliam began this race....
Mays Gilliam  開始這次競選 ----
That's my man!
這是我的男人。
Excuse me, please.
對不起，讓一讓。
-I've been looking for you. -I was looking for you.
- 我到處找你。
-This is amazing! -It's amazing.
- Mays ，一切都太美妙了。 - 是呀。
It's incredible.
真是不可思議。
-What you were up against. -The odds!
- 你是怎麼闖過來的？ - 不信邪。
I can't wait to start working, and do I have a job for you!
我不能等，馬上要工作。 你要我給你一個職務嗎？
I don't know what to say. What department do you want me to work in? Finance?
是嗎？真是太好了。 哪個部門你想交給我管呢，財政部？
No, that's not good enough for you.
不，那個位置不太好。
-Foreign Affairs? -No, not Foreign Affairs.
- 外交部？ - 不行，外交部，不行。
I thought you could do something real good in Security!
我以為你可以做得很好的地方是--- 保安。
You suck!
大混蛋！
We'd like you to run for President.
我們喜歡你去競選總統。
Sometimes, you don't know if people like you for you.
有時候，你真不知道，人們是否為了愛你而愛你。
I like you for you.
我嘛，是為了愛你而愛你的。
Thanks a lot.
非常感謝。
Get your hand off my ass, boy!
為什麼把手放在我的屁股上，孩子!
Wait!
等一下。
Oh, my God, you are everywhere. Look at you!
噢，天哪，到處都是你。你看你呀。
What's the first thing you're going to do, Mr. President?
你第一件要幹的是什麼事啊，總統先生？
The first thing I'll do is make you my First Lady.
第一件要做的事就是請你當上我的第一夫人。
-Don't you play with me like that. -I'm not playing.
- Mays ， 你不能跟我開這個玩笑。 - 沒開玩笑啊。
You can't do that!
你怎麼可以這樣做呢？
I'm the government. I can do anything.
我是政府，我可以做任何事。
Get ready for...
大家準備好，
the 2005 Presidential Inaugural Ball.
參加 2005  年總統就職典禮。
Ladies and gentlemen, the President of the United States of America...
女士們，先生們， 美利堅合眾國的總統 ---
Mays Gilliam, and his future First Wifey...
Mays Gilliam 和他的未來第一夫人 ----
Lisa Clark!
Lisa Clark!
Look at him now, man Ain't this great
現在你來看一看啊，夥計， 這事偉大不偉大？
Biggest man in town He's the head of state
城裡最大的人呀，他就是國家元首。
They come from all around just for one handshake
人們從四面八方湧來，為的是握一握手。
Look at him now He's the head of state
你來看一看他吧，他是國家元首。
That's me, Mays Gilliam...
這是我，Mays Gilliam...
President of the United States of America.
美利堅合眾國的總統。
North America.
北美洲的。
-Who did you vote for? -For what?
- 你選的是誰？ - 選他做什麼？
-For President. -Of what?
- 做總統。 - 哪國的？
-Of the United States.
-  合眾國。 - 哪個洲的合眾國？
-Of America. -What America?
- 美利堅州的。 - 哪個美利堅洲？
North America.
北美利堅洲。
Slick, I don't vote. You gonna buy some of this meat, or what?
我才不去呢。 你想買我的肉嗎，別的要什麼？
You can't trust nobody. Everybody's trying to rob you. Nobody!
誰也不能相信。 每個人都想搶你。誰也別相信。
That guy right there! Don't trust him!
那邊那個人，別相信他。
Can't trust no-damn-body!
不要相信任何人。
America is taking advantage of you!
美國在利用你，你，還有你。
You can go to war when you're 18, but you can't have a drink till you're 21!
你年滿18歲，你就得上戰場， 可你想喝點酒，等到 21 歲吧。
-That ain't right! -Right! So, let me get this straight.
- 這事情不正常。 -  對！ 我來改一改。
You're 18 years old. You go to war.
你 18 歲了？ 打仗去。
You come back. Your leg is chopped off!
你回來的時候，一條腿已經裁掉了。
You got a damn nub!
你成了殘疾人。
Everywhere you go they say, "What's up, nubby?"
你到哪裡，人們都會對你說，怎麼樣啊，小殘？
You get to the bar and say, "Bartender, can I have a drink?"
你到酒吧，說， 酒保，給我來杯酒。
He looks you up and down and says, "l got to see some lD."
他上下一打量，說， 給我看你的證件。
ID? You mean to tell me a one-legged teenager can't have a drink?
證件？ 你的意思是說，單腿青年不能喝酒？
-That ain't right! -Where is the nub?
- 這事情不正常。 - 小殘在哪裡？
Prescription drugs, I'll lower the prices. Let me explain something else to you.
我要降低處方藥品的價格。 請聽我的解釋：
You can survive a stroke...
你中風了，經過搶救，活了，
but the high prices of medicine will give you a heart attack.
但是昂貴的醫療費用，卻馬上讓你 心肌梗塞。
America is the richest, most powerful nation on earth.
美國是世界上最富有的、最強大的國家。
If America was a car, it would be a Bentley...
如果美國是一輛小汽車，美國就是一輛本特利，
sitting on chrome doves, with TVs in the headrests...
它放在鍍鉻的鴿子上，頭墊裡面裝電視，
and a fine, naked Puerto Rican girl feeding you grapes!
一個美麗的，全裸的波多黎各姑娘 正在餵你吃葡萄！
Ain't nothing better than that! Ain't nothing ever been better than that!
比這更美的事還有嗎？
Most opponents are saying your brother destroyed any chance of winning...
大多數對手都說 你的兄弟把你贏的機會都給破壞掉了，
by naming you as his running mate. Why?
因為他把你選作競選搭檔。 為什麼你要這麼做？
-Why'd your brother make you anchorman? -I don't have--
- 為什麼你的兄弟要讓你做主播？ - 我沒有兄弟 ---
You said it was your brother. I did my homework as well, okay?
你說過那是你兄弟。 你備課，我也備過課，知道嗎？
You got your job same way I got mine.
你找到工作的方法同我的一樣。
-I'm not running for public office. -I'm not running for anchorman.
- 我又不競選公職。 - 我又不去當主播。